<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>C0DET1GER</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-03-21T23:50:38.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>C0DET1GER</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A day before USACO Open</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2025/03/21/A-day-before-USACO-Open/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2025/03/21/A-day-before-USACO-Open/</id>
    <published>2025-03-21T23:14:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-03-21T23:50:38.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was considering not to write this blog post since it could affect my feelings, leading to a worse performance tomorrow.</p><span id="more"></span><p>This post isn’t really that much about USACO and competitive programming though, since the only  thing I’ve done was being anxious.</p><h2 id="CMIMC"><a href="#CMIMC" class="headerlink" title="CMIMC"></a>CMIMC</h2><p>And then there’s CMIMC. The trip was a fun experience overall (this was actually the first travel competition I’ve ever attended). On Friday our plane got delayed so we had lunch at like 4. Then we went to play frisbee and later went to estimathon (we won!). </p><p>The Theoretical Computer Science round was kind of interesting because I’ve never done one of these rounds before (except for practicing in math team). But it turned out that we didn’t do too good on that round either despite me being a USACO main. On team the only thing I did was p1 and solving p2 at the last second but not having enough time to change our wrong answer.</p><p>During individuals I ABSOLUTELY SOLD (distribution was strictly less than 434 oops). I probably should’ve been in Lexington Epsilon. I can’t really say anything though since CMIMC (and perhaps math in general) isn’t as important as USACO is to me or USA(J)MO is to other people, so I probably shouldn’t be ranting too much.</p><p>On our way back my seat was changed for some reason, making me sit with a stranger instead of Lexington people. The wifi also didn’t work on our way back, so I basically just idled for an hour.</p><h2 id="Other"><a href="#Other" class="headerlink" title="Other"></a>Other</h2><p>Obviously my 226.5 JMO index was lower than the 233.5 cutoff, but since I wasn’t prepared anyway and would spend more time on preparing for USACO, I don’t really feel too bad about that. I also probably got a 10 in F=ma (got p1, p4, p6, p8, p9, p10, p11, and guessed the rest), which is much lower than a 15 so I don’t have anything to regret about.</p><p>There was also picoCTF and vyx7 &amp; other LexMACS people admitted orz (33th place in US High School or below). In the beginning of the window I just stole all the easy problems and pretended that I contributed. I’ll (probably) also become one of the LIT organizers which means that I probably can’t participate in LIT 2024 standard round even if it somehow miraculously happens.</p><p>Unfortunately, my GPA fell off so now I likely won’t have one higher than 4.1 anymore.</p><p>The only thing I can hope for now is to not do bad in USACO Open, hopefully a 300+ (or even 400+) score. I don’t want all my luck in December, January and February to be for nothing.</p><p>My birthday also passed recently, so now I’m 15 years old.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was considering not to write this blog post since it could affect my feelings, leading to a worse performance tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="general update" scheme="http://example.com/categories/general-update/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>USACO February Plat</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2025/02/27/USACO-February-Plat/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2025/02/27/USACO-February-Plat/</id>
    <published>2025-02-27T21:04:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-02-27T21:05:56.334Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Camp when?</p><span id="more"></span><p>Score: 494, the distribution was 333 / 56 / 105</p><p>The contest went pretty well, perhaps even better than the January contest. I quickly (in the first 30 minutes) got the main observation for problem 1. Although I proceeded to spend 1 hour on implementation, I just felt confident that I could pull a &gt;400 score again with the 2.5 hours remaining.</p><p>So I was pretty calm and relaxed and got 494 with 1 hour remaining. Maybe some parts of me thought this was good enough, while some other parts of me still thought I should try to full solve another problem, since this would probably be enough to make it to the leaderboard.</p><p>I just thought p2 was probably actually easy and it had a lot of subtasks that could hopefully get me to a &gt;500 score so I spent the remaining hour doing p2 and got 0 points. But I guess this was fine since I still don’t think I would’ve gotten p3 anyway.</p><p>I feel the style of platinum contests, or perhaps even gold, have changed a lot. At least noticably there hasn’t been as much graph problems (0 in plat, not sure how many in gold), and the problems are more ad-hoc in general. Perhaps this benefits me since I’m probably an ad-hoc main, but this would probably mean that even if I somehow make USACO camp, I would still have to rely on this kind of different style to perform well.</p><p>Hopefully I don’t throw USACO Open along with my camp chances <span class="github-emoji"><span>🙏</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f64f.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> People say an average of &gt;300 should make but I don’t know how much more USACO open is weighted so it’s a little scary. Why isn’t the cutoffs for camp disclosed <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span>.</p><p>I also hope USACO could let us know our rank within people in the United States who took the contest (maybe certified). Last time I got 421, which was apparently a very common score, and it was rank 49. I have no idea how this converts to the rank in the United States (or perhaps if we limit it to certified people).</p><p>Reposting manifold market<br><a href="https://manifold.markets/C0DET1GER/will-i-make-usaco-camp-in-2025?play=true">https://manifold.markets/C0DET1GER/will-i-make-usaco-camp-in-2025?play=true</a></p><p>My manifold net worth tripled in February which was … nice?</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Camp when?&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="competitive programming" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/"/>
    
    <category term="usaco" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/usaco/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>AIME II 2025</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2025/02/14/AIME-II-2025/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2025/02/14/AIME-II-2025/</id>
    <published>2025-02-15T01:12:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-02-15T01:16:51.339Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>because we had a snow day</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Some-Stuff"><a href="#Some-Stuff" class="headerlink" title="Some Stuff"></a>Some Stuff</h2><p>Originally we were going to take aime i but because of snow day we had to take aime ii. This may be kind of good because historically aime ii has lower cutoffs (and I don’t feel the tests are harder). But maybe this time cracked regions are taking aime ii which will inflate the cutoffs idk. </p><p>So I had aime ii and f=ma on the same day (f=ma was delayed to like 5:45-7:00), which probably didn’t make that much of a difference since there’s no way I could’ve gotten &gt;=14 in f=ma. (I’m just bad like that)</p><p>I didn’t really expect anything to be honest. Like of course my goal is to make jmo, but I knew that it’s not that likely considering how I would’ve thrown both AMCs if not because I was lucky (and still didn’t get 140+ for AMC 10A, but I guess 136.5 is fine). Also that I haven’t been doing that much math lately since my main objective is to make usaco camp I guess (impossible)</p><p>In last year’s aime, I sillied (maybe some of them don’t really count as sillies) my way from 8 to 5, giving me like a 170 index. That’s why I didn’t really expect myself to make jmo, and maybe that turned out to be the right mindset, since I wasn’t too nervous before / during the test.</p><h2 id="AIME"><a href="#AIME" class="headerlink" title="AIME"></a>AIME</h2><p>For p1, in the beginning my lengths were all wrong because I kept misreading the letters in the lenghts. But at least I finally managed to solve it after like 7 minutes. Then I did p2-4 in the next 15 minutes and found out there’s two geo in a row.</p><p>I kind of wanted to skip both since I’m a geo antimain and I didn’t want the geos to give me emotional damage for the entire test. But then I remembered that it’s just p5 and p6 which will hopefully not be too hard. So I spent 20 more minutes and did both.</p><p>Then I just kind of skimmed through the next 5 problems and found that 4 / maybe 5 of them were combo which somehow boosted my confidence. And they turned out not to be too hard so I got 7, 8, 9, and 11 in the next 30 minutes or so (I didn’t know how to p10 because all I could think of was a 16 * 8 * 3 dp skull)</p><p>So now I had 105 minutes left and did 10 problems, but I thought the ten I did were easy so I probably needed more if I wanted to get lucky and make jmo. I didn’t really spend a lot of time on p12 and p14 because geo. So I started trying to do p13. </p><p>Then I suddenly wanted to go to the bathroom but somehow thought that I had to submit early if I wanted to go so I held it for 30 minutes. Until I figured I should actually ask and turned out I could go without submitting early <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> (and this submitting early rule probably only applied to my elementary school exams). Going to the bathroom earlier probably wouldn’t have made a difference though since I was trying to do p13 the entire time.</p><p>I kind of wanted to do more problems, but then thought a 236.5 would likely be enough to qualify for jmo, but that also meant I needed 0 sillies which is impossible. So I went to check my work and caught 4 sillies (p4 multiply by 1/3 instead of 3, p5 I did multiplication wrong, p9… don’t know what to say it’s just entirely wrong, and p11 I had 95 because I forgot about numbers that weren’t divisors of 24)</p><p>This was satisfying, but also extremely terrifying at the same time. This meant my aime score would’ve been like 4 points lower (at least I thought it would be 4 points lower). These 40 minutes of checking really made a big difference.</p><p>Then I proceeded to think about p10 since it’s the only combo problem left. Got it in about 10 minutes, and I immediately checked and caught a silly. Spent about 5 more minutes and found that I only had 10 minutes left so I couldn’t really do anything. Well, I checked my work but didn’t find any more sillies.</p><h2 id="Reflection"><a href="#Reflection" class="headerlink" title="Reflection"></a>Reflection</h2><p>so distribution was like<br>11111 11011 00000 (got p8 and p11 wrong)</p><p>For p8 I forgot that 55 existed so I wrote 800 <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> I wouldn’t count that as a silly but idk<br>For p11 I remembered that 8 was 0 the first time but then completely forgot that it was 0 when I was correcting it <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> </p><p>So my jmo index went from 246.5 to 226.5</p><p>Definitely not optimal, but considering that I didn’t even anticipate jmo, this was better than I thought. But perhaps qualifying or not wouldn’t matter that much either, since I’m bad at proofs and stuff –&gt; will probably get like a 0 on jmo anyway <del>and flagged a cheater</del></p><p>And I might’ve been cooked in F=ma, we don’t talk about that</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;because we had a snow day&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="math comp" scheme="http://example.com/categories/math-comp/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>USACO 2025 January</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2025/01/29/USACO-2025-January/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2025/01/29/USACO-2025-January/</id>
    <published>2025-01-29T19:43:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-03-01T00:12:14.855Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spoiler: I got a positive score <span class="github-emoji"><span>👍</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><span id="more"></span><p>Score: 421 (distribution is like 333 / 26 / 62)</p><p>I think I performed okay in this contest, at first I thought that 421 was pretty good but turned out it’s probably because p1 was very very easy (I thought so too). The thing is I worshipped CodeTiger before contest and got one problem, <del>so <em>surely</em> if I worshipped a bit more I would’ve gotten 2…</del></p><p>But the thing is many people unfortunately skipped p1 in the beginning (like me). I only went back to look at p1 (and solve it after like 30 minutes) because I was so desparate with my sub 100 score.</p><p>I still don’t know why I didn’t get subtask 2 for problem 2 though, will probably have to wait until sunday when they release the testcases and stuff to find out. I made the right observation, but still couldn’t manage to solve even the subtask <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>I hope to camp this year, although that seems pretty much impossible considering my skill. <del>But I’ve heard that they considered improvement arcs so hopefully 767 in gold –&gt; 421 in plat is good enough.</del> I guess I’ll have to get lucky in two more contests, or maybe get extremely lucky in open.</p><p>MITIT also happened recently, we were CodeTiger ORZ ORZ ORZ so we got first in hs beginner and second in overall beginner. Kind of sold for not being able to do p8 and p9, but a 900 isn’t really that different from a 735 as long as we got first place I guess</p><p>Also just realized that AIME is next week, and I forgot to do any OTIS <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>And I made a manifold market lol<br><a href="https://manifold.markets/C0DET1GER/will-i-make-usaco-camp-in-2025?play=true">https://manifold.markets/C0DET1GER/will-i-make-usaco-camp-in-2025?play=true</a><br>buy no for free mana.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: I got a positive score &lt;span class=&quot;github-emoji&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;👍&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44d.png?v8&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; onerror=&quot;this.parent.classList.add(&#39;github-emoji-fallback&#39;)&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="competitive programming" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/"/>
    
    <category term="usaco" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/usaco/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Virtual - BOI 2024</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/31/Virtual-BOI-2024/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/31/Virtual-BOI-2024/</id>
    <published>2025-01-01T01:21:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-01-01T02:28:20.073Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unfortunately, due to certain circumstances, this will be the last blog of this year.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Basically I decided that I should actually be productive during the christmas break. I also virtualed a USACO plat contest, paken 2023 day 1, paken 2023 day 3, and JOI 2023 but I’m kinda too lazy to write so many blogs.</p><h1 id="Day-1"><a href="#Day-1" class="headerlink" title="Day 1"></a>Day 1</h1><p><a href="https://cses.fi/file/9efc5cc4448bd5ee4de86929c7e9d4650a173011b07b2588903633f7afa428cb">Tasks here</a></p><h2 id="Virtual"><a href="#Virtual" class="headerlink" title="Virtual"></a>Virtual</h2><details><summary> spoiler </summary><p>After reading all the problems, pA felt kind of dp-ish, pB’s probably some weird geometry stuff which I’m really bad at, and pC was probably also some kind of dp + perhaps BIT, but I could only think of the O(N^2) sol atp.</p><p>Estimated difficulty: C &lt; A &lt;&lt; B, so I tried to solve C first.</p><p>In problem C I kept aiming for some O(NlogN) solution but then after a few minutes I finally figured out the O(NsqrtN) solution.</p><h3 id="0-35-C-58"><a href="#0-35-C-58" class="headerlink" title="0:35 C 58"></a>0:35 C <font color="yellow">58</font></h3><p>Passing all subtasks except for the O(N^2) one was very absurd, so I wondered whether it was a modulo issue</p><h3 id="0-37-C-100"><a href="#0-37-C-100" class="headerlink" title="0:37 C 100"></a>0:37 C <font color="lightgreen">100</font></h3><p>That was nice.</p><p>Before dumping a potential 4 hours into problem A, I thought I shouldn’t make the same mistake as TOI 2024 (only aiming for full scores instead of subtasks, which only gave me a score of 200/500 in the end)</p><p>Therefore, I looked at subtask 1 in pB and guessed that the answer was the rectangle area minus 1</p><h3 id="0-49-B-0"><a href="#0-49-B-0" class="headerlink" title="0:49 B 0"></a>0:49 B <font color="red">0</font></h3><p>whoops, maybe that guess was wrong then<br>I then drew a few cases by hand and found out that I overthought and the answer was actually -1</p><h3 id="0-53-B-1"><a href="#0-53-B-1" class="headerlink" title="0:53 B 1"></a>0:53 B <font color="orange">1</font></h3><p>At least I passed the subtask, although 1 point isn’t really any better than 0</p><p>Then after drawing a few more cases I made an “educated guess” (without proof because I’m bad at geo / linear alg / whatever) that the answer for subtask 3 is (gcd of differences in x) times (gcd of differnces in y).</p><h3 id="1-04-B-10"><a href="#1-04-B-10" class="headerlink" title="1:04 B 10"></a>1:04 B <font color="orange">10</font></h3><p>Oh wait there isn’t 自動聯集 ??? (automated subtask union or whatever that’s called in english, honestly i don’t know)</p><h3 id="1-05-B-11"><a href="#1-05-B-11" class="headerlink" title="1:05 B 11"></a>1:05 B <font color="orange">11</font></h3><p>Well, I tried my best, at least I probably wouldn’t regret not spending more time on this problem afterwards, so I started thinking about pA.</p><p>I mindsolved subtask 1, and subtasks 2 and 3 could be done with some priority_queue. I decided to implement subtasks 2 and 3 first.</p><h3 id="2-14-A-0"><a href="#2-14-A-0" class="headerlink" title="2:14 A 0"></a>2:14 A <font color="red">0</font></h3><p>Just some kind of out-of-bounds error</p><h3 id="2-21-A-29"><a href="#2-21-A-29" class="headerlink" title="2:21 A 29"></a>2:21 A <font color="orange">29</font></h3><p>I then went back to implement subtask 1</p><h3 id="2-25-B-40"><a href="#2-25-B-40" class="headerlink" title="2:25 B 40"></a>2:25 B <font color="orange">40</font></h3><p>Currently my score is 40 / 11 / 100</p><p>Despite how I said “I spent enough time on pB”, I still felt that 11 points was way too low, so I threw pA aside temporarily (which turned out to be a very good decision)</p><p>After drawing out a few more cases, I guessed again that the answer for subtask 2 was (the triangle area formed by the three points) * 2</p><h3 id="2-49-B-11"><a href="#2-49-B-11" class="headerlink" title="2:49 B 11"></a>2:49 B <font color="orange">11</font></h3><p>I forgot that when the triangle area is 0 I’m supposed to output -1</p><h3 id="2-55-B-21"><a href="#2-55-B-21" class="headerlink" title="2:55 B 21"></a>2:55 B <font color="orange">21</font></h3><p>I then went on guessing that by combining subtasks 2 and 3, the answer is 2 * (gcd of all triangle areas). I tried proving it, but failed miserably</p><h3 id="3-01-B-50"><a href="#3-01-B-50" class="headerlink" title="3:01 B 50"></a>3:01 B <font color="yellow">50</font></h3><p>How were almost all my guesses correct? I then decided to use some randomization to pass subtask 5 (because I forgot that I could actually fix one point in the triangle)</p><h3 id="3-07-B-65"><a href="#3-07-B-65" class="headerlink" title="3:07 B 65"></a>3:07 B <font color="yellow">65</font></h3><p>This gave me some hope and I tried using some better (?) randomizations, trying to obtain the full score and failed (I thought the official solution would involve randomization smh)</p><p>65 was probably decent enough anyway, so I decided to spend the rest of the time on pA. I came up with the solution for subtask 4 but there was like 998244353 bugs in my code.</p><h3 id="4-34-A-69"><a href="#4-34-A-69" class="headerlink" title="4:34 A 69"></a>4:34 A <font color="yellow">69</font></h3><p>And I spent the remainder of the time doing essentially nothing.</p></details><h2 id="Reflection"><a href="#Reflection" class="headerlink" title="Reflection"></a>Reflection</h2><details><summary> spoiler </summary><p>Final score: 69 / 65 / 100<br>Total: 234<br>Day 1 rank 5</p><p>This is much higher than what I should’ve gotten, at least my score would’ve been 170 without guessing</p><p>Also less people solved pA than I originally thought, and scores generally aren’t that high on pB. I guess I should improve my math though, otherwise my score would probably have been pretty low.</p><p>Also I should be better at implementation <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> I wasted a lot of time on debugging, especially pA (I didn’t include all my submission scores since then the blog would be even longer)</p></details><h1 id="Day-2"><a href="#Day-2" class="headerlink" title="Day 2"></a>Day 2</h1><p><a href="https://cses.fi/file/e3b8350c10f2e8780b405978ebfc984e4dd878d5c9c65d6a33f95cf93af5ab25">Tasks here</a></p><p>After Day 1 I actually gained a bit of confidence in my poor OI ability, maybe perhaps too much</p><h2 id="Virtual-1"><a href="#Virtual-1" class="headerlink" title="Virtual"></a>Virtual</h2><details><summary> spoiler </summary><p>The entire problemset just felt harder than day 1 for some reason (although it turned out that a great amount of people performed better on day 2 than day 1) The only thing I could think of was the O(N^2) solution for pA (40 pts). The implementation for pB seemed cancerous, and I didn’t have any idea for pC.</p><p>I made a few WA submissions</p><h3 id="0-50-A-40"><a href="#0-50-A-40" class="headerlink" title="0:50 A 40"></a>0:50 A <font color="orange">40</font></h3><p>Then it turned out that subtask 4 wasn’t that hard</p><h3 id="0-53-A-53"><a href="#0-53-A-53" class="headerlink" title="0:53 A 53"></a>0:53 A <font color="yellow">53</font></h3><p>I was really afraid that I would end up with a sub-100 score, so I still decided to move on and try pB. Subtask 1 (4 pts) was just a rectangle, but I read the problem incorrectly and originally thought the problem was asking for the number of squares one can put in the rectangle.</p><h3 id="1-14-B-4"><a href="#1-14-B-4" class="headerlink" title="1:14 B 4"></a>1:14 B <font color="orange">4</font></h3><p>Subtask 2 seemed like a lot of casework but I decided to try it anyway. Wasted like an hour and got 0 points so I moved on.</p><p>For pC, subtask 1 was just enumeration, and later came up with the solution for subtask 5</p><h3 id="2-29-C-20"><a href="#2-29-C-20" class="headerlink" title="2:29 C 20"></a>2:29 C <font color="orange">20</font></h3><p>Then I went back to problem B subtask 2 since I thought nothing could’ve gone wrong. I couldn’t figure out anything until at the three hour mark when I found that I actually MISREAD THE PROBLEM <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><h3 id="3-05-B-13"><a href="#3-05-B-13" class="headerlink" title="3:05 B 13"></a>3:05 B <font color="orange">13</font></h3><p>My current score is 53 + 13 + 20 = 86. I might actually get a sub-100 score if things continue like this. At the same time (3 hours), my day 1 score was above 200, which is very depressing</p><p>At least I was sure I finally understood the problem correctly, and found out that subtask 3 was actually quite similar to subtask 2.</p><h3 id="3-20-B-24"><a href="#3-20-B-24" class="headerlink" title="3:20 B 24"></a>3:20 B <font color="orange">24</font></h3><p>I then spent some more time on a solution for subtask 5 which turned out to be wrong, leaving me with less than 1.5 hours left. I found out that I probably spent less than 30 minutes on pC so I went back and came up with the solution for subtasks 1-3.</p><h3 id="4-13-C-56"><a href="#4-13-C-56" class="headerlink" title="4:13 C 56"></a>4:13 C <font color="yellow">56</font></h3><p>This problem is the only one (in day 2) where my submissions don’t repeat their scores. My score is finally higher than 100 (133), but is still pretty low imo. The solution for subtask 4 (14 pts) is also very similar but perhaps a bit harder to implement. Soon, I also figured out how I could obtain the remaining 47 points for pA. </p><p>Now I have like 40 minutes left, and I can probably decide to do pA (perhaps more risky?) or pC. Upon contemplation, I made the worst choice possible: try to solve pB.</p><p>Why? Maybe I’m inexperienced in OI. Maybe I’m greedy and think that 40 minutes is still plenty of time left. Maybe I just thought I could get lucky like day 1 and get a lot of points by guessing. Anyway, I wasted more time to get 0 points on pB until I found it was probably too late to implement (and finish debugging from past experience) the full solution for pA.</p><h3 id="4-44-A-Compilation-Error"><a href="#4-44-A-Compilation-Error" class="headerlink" title="4:44 A Compilation Error"></a>4:44 A <font color="red">Compilation Error</font></h3><p>This was so weird (and maybe funny). My code in xcode ran perfectly, and I don’t know what I was thinking but didn’t look at the error message and instead stared at my code for errors.</p><h3 id="4-51-A-53"><a href="#4-51-A-53" class="headerlink" title="4:51 A 53"></a>4:51 A <font color="yellow">53</font></h3><p>Then I couldn’t find the bug until the end of the contest.</p><hr><h3 id="5-02-A-74"><a href="#5-02-A-74" class="headerlink" title="5:02 A 74"></a>5:02 A <font color="yellow">74</font></h3><p>Turned out I forgot to add 1 somewhere. Well, too bad, the contest ended already. An extra 21 points wouldn’t have made me gold anyway.</p></details><h2 id="Reflection-1"><a href="#Reflection-1" class="headerlink" title="Reflection"></a>Reflection</h2><details><summary> spoiler </summary><p>Final score: 53 / 24 / 56<br>Total: 133<br>Day 2 rank 17</p><p>This was actually so bad. I also didn’t expect so many people to perform better in day 2 compared to day 1. My maximum score in day 2 across all problems is lower than the minimum in day 1 <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>I think the main problem was that I spent most of the time trying pB without even getting a lot of points. Perhaps I should’ve given up earlier and worked on pA and pC instead.</p><p>My luck on day 1 might’ve actually destroyed my day 2 performance, since it was because of how my guess obtained so many points that made me willing to spend time and guess wrong solutions on day 2 as well.</p><p>Also I made a lot more submissions than listed in the blog, and by a lot I mean</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/xfdxVtZ.png" alt="image"></p><p>There’s no penalty, so it doesn’t matter … right?</p><p>I totally regret the decision I made when there was 40 minutes left, I don’t know where the confidence came from that made me think I could get all 64 points in like 20 minutes.</p><p>Perhaps I’m not good at CP after all.</p></details><h1 id="Final-Results"><a href="#Final-Results" class="headerlink" title="Final Results"></a>Final Results</h1><details><summary> spoiler </summary><p>Total: 367<br>Overall rank: 9 (high silver?)</p><p>Wasn’t any close to gold anyway, would’ve needed all 67 points. My score on pB was really kind of low despite I tried for more than 3 hours probably.</p><p>I never learn the lesson. I shouldn’t get stuck on one single problem. Hopefully I can at least be happy with my performance in the next USACO in January.</p><p>Doing OI virtuals is somewhat fun though ngl, but unfortunately I’m very bad at these. Perhaps doing more virtual contests would help me come up with some kind of optimal contest strategy? Or maybe what I should do at each weird scenarios? idk actually, and idt I have that much time after semester 1 ends (4 less study blocks <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span>)</p></details>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to certain circumstances, this will be the last blog of this year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="competitive programming" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/"/>
    
    <category term="virtual contest" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/virtual-contest/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>USACO Plat yayy</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/22/USACO-Plat-yayy/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/22/USACO-Plat-yayy/</id>
    <published>2024-12-22T14:11:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-01-29T19:45:45.114Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>nicee!!!</p><span id="more"></span><p>Turns out 716 qualified for plat (cutoff is 700 this time). Only 20 promotions in USA which seems pretty much unexpected, but still pretty happy about it.</p><p>I need to lock in during the Christmas break or I’ll likely get a 0 in plat sadge</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;nicee!!!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="competitive programming" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/"/>
    
    <category term="usaco" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/usaco/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>USACO December oops</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/17/USACO-december-oops/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/17/USACO-december-oops/</id>
    <published>2024-12-17T23:42:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-01-29T19:47:16.219Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did not underperform, it’s just my skill issue.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Still not much to say really, still sad</p><p>Score: 716 (333 / 50 / 333 distrib)</p><p>I feel that I’m probably not promoting tbh</p><p>Basically I looked at all three problems first then figured that p3 seems to be pretty well known and I might’ve even solved it before. Then I spent like 40 minutes on trying some random greedy that did not work. Then I decided to go look at the other problems.</p><p>First p1. I looked at the subtasks and thought that it could do with sqrt and wrote some kind of Nsqrt(N)log^2(N)-ish solution (I thought that there’s only one log because I suck at time complexity, which was also why I decided to implement it). It only failed three testcases. I moved on because three testcases didn’t really seem to matter right now.</p><p>This was about at the 1 hour mark since I passed (most of) p1 relatively quickly. Then I looked at p2 and had no idea. I thought of dp for subtask 2 but nothing beyond that. I decided that “p3 must actually be very easy” and put 2 more additional hours on that problem. I just started having random ideas and found out that greedy actually worked. It’s a rather short implementation so I ACed the problem at around the 3 hour mark.</p><p>At this time my score was about 600, and I figured that the 3 testcases might actually matter. (At this point I still didn’t notice that my time complexity had two logs) I thought that it must’ve been a constant problem, so I removed the “define int long long” and other unnecessary code to pass all testcases.</p><p>I had 666 points, and since p1 and p3 seemed to be relatively easy (although I had a skill issue and spent 3 hours on them), I thought the cutoff would be around 800. This also meant that I would have to solve subtask 3 in the remaining hour. This didn’t seem too bad, but I thought I should solve subtasks 1 and 2 first to secure a score above 700. Then, since I had a significant skill issue I spent about 30 minutes to solve those subtasks after I had the idea for dp (the main thing was that my solution was different and implementation heavy I guess).</p><p>Then I just spent the remaining 30 minutes thinking about how to solve subtask 3 and not solving it (which is essentially doing nothing)</p><p>After the contest, people seem to say that the cutoff will be around 750. I hope that the cutoff is 700, although it seems realistically impossible ngl. </p><p>Still hope that the cutoff is 700 (or lower) <span class="github-emoji"><span>🥺</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f97a.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> I still want a chance to camp in 9th grade, even if it’s 0.000000001%</p><p>I also learned that I’m not the only CF master clowning in USACO gold</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did not underperform, it’s just my skill issue.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="competitive programming" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/"/>
    
    <category term="usaco" scheme="http://example.com/categories/competitive-programming/usaco/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mid December Update</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/13/Mid-December-Update/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/13/Mid-December-Update/</id>
    <published>2024-12-14T00:29:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-01-13T04:14:50.154Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>found that I haven’t posted for a long time, although there’s probably like only one person reading this (myself)</p><span id="more"></span><p>Oh well there isn’t much to say so I guess I won’t make any subtitles</p><p>Basically I did get DHR in 10A (and did not in 10B), which is probably the only thing I’m happy about recently. Totally threw in BMT, and I don’t seem prepared myself for USACO. I also might be cooked in Literature <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>And NHSPC (a Taiwanese contest for high schoolers) also happened recently, @the_researching_pooh @69manweiwei @leolin orz</p><p>Finally, hopefully I get lucky enough tomorrow and advance into Platinum :) I don’t know why but advancing really seems so hard and impossible to me, I can’t even AK when I look at past problems now. And LMT is also happening tomorrow, but because it clashes with USACO certified period I’m not going, sad</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;found that I haven’t posted for a long time, although there’s probably like only one person reading this (myself)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="general update" scheme="http://example.com/categories/general-update/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Quarter 1 Recap</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/11/15/Quarter-1-Recap/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/11/15/Quarter-1-Recap/</id>
    <published>2024-11-15T19:58:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T20:16:17.025Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>writing now although quarter 1 ended on 11/8</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Social"><a href="#Social" class="headerlink" title="Social"></a>Social</h2><p>Alright seems that the “not socializing with homeroom people” strategy is not working out smh</p><p>I don’t know whether this is normal but I only have one person in my homeroom I share science with, and zero in all other classes (excluding PE). I also barely share studies with people in my homeroom.</p><p>Another thing is that our male-female ratio is like 1:2, and I’m not the type of person that talks with girls a lot, which makes things even worse.</p><p>Other classes are much better though than homeroom imo, at least I talk to people.</p><h2 id="CP"><a href="#CP" class="headerlink" title="CP"></a>CP</h2><p>I didn’t really do CP a lot this quarter, I guess I will fall back to specialist on CF soon.</p><p>I haven’t really done any contests recently after I reached master, maybe just one AtCoder contest and an HSCSA contest. I feel I should practice more OI though, I haven’t practiced a lot and will probably throw OI contests for not getting any partials.</p><p>Also LIT is currently in<del>de</del>finitely postponed, so I might fail my C1 goal miserably <span class="github-emoji"><span>🤡</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f921.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> Hopefully it will eventually happen, although I might still not get first in middle school division because I’m bad.</p><h2 id="Academics"><a href="#Academics" class="headerlink" title="Academics"></a>Academics</h2><p>Not too bad I guess.</p><p>In the beginning my grades were bad for Earth Science but it went back up later after all the tests and other stuff. On the contrary, my humanities (Literature + Social Studies) grades gradually dropped as the quarter passed. At least I successfully kept my GPA above 4. </p><p>Current GPA: 4.13, might still change though since grades are not final until like 11/18. I’m pretty glad that my teachers aren’t too harsh on grading.</p><h2 id="Math"><a href="#Math" class="headerlink" title="Math"></a>Math</h2><p>I feel there’s much more math contests here, and math team people are very orz. </p><p>A good thing about LHS I guess is that there’s a lot of orz people and I can learn from them instead of having to do everything myself. Also that I can be carried in contests like HMMT which feels very nice.</p><p>The tryouts went out nicely for me, at least I didn’t silly too much, which placed me in teams that may be higher than my capability. I’ll try my best not to do nothing I guess.</p><p>I originally thought that math team had meetings too often, but because of the half days and all the breaks it turns out not to be that many.</p><p>And I kind of stopped doing OTIS after school started which is bad, I’ve completed 2 units after the summer break and only 2 units after school started. I’m currently like level 31 and I don’t know how good that is.</p><hr><p><del>btw I’m not trying to say anything is a scam or something</del></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;writing now although quarter 1 ended on 11/8&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="quarter" scheme="http://example.com/categories/quarter/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>HMMT</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/11/10/HMMT/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/11/10/HMMT/</id>
    <published>2024-11-10T23:25:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T19:29:09.524Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>yayy</p><span id="more"></span><p>I’m in Lex Gamma, and I’m probably the only person in the team (or maybe among everyone in LHS that came to HMMT this year) that has never competed in HMMT. Everyone in the team is way better than me tho, so I’m ready to be carried in team and guts round and drag the team down in individual rounds.</p><h2 id="General-Round"><a href="#General-Round" class="headerlink" title="General Round"></a>General Round</h2><p>I did problems 1-6 and 8 and didn’t even look at the other problems. They announced the answers right after the test ended and I got 3 and 6 wrong which is like sad. I felt soo good when I remembered about the “15” case for problem 6 and thought that many people would probably forget about that one, but turned out that I forgot about the 195 case so I was like one off. I wouldn’t call that a silly though, as it’s my own skill issue, but I probably lost like 6 points because of this. At least I found the right pattern in problem 8 which is not too bad.</p><h2 id="Theme-Round"><a href="#Theme-Round" class="headerlink" title="Theme Round"></a>Theme Round</h2><p>0 sillies in this round, but still bad</p><p>I only looked at 1-7, and 9 (because it’s combo) and didn’t know how to do 6 because I’m bad at geo. Turned out I spent too much time on 9, and didn’t really do it the right way. Although I solved 6 problems my distrib is like very bad, so I’m probably the lowest in the team.</p><h2 id="Team-Round"><a href="#Team-Round" class="headerlink" title="Team Round"></a>Team Round</h2><p>tnag carry orz</p><p>I probably didn’t do anything, except p1 p4 and maybe p8, which other teammates could probably have done quickly without me. We (tnag) also perfed teamround with like 5 or 10 minutes left which was nice. We ended up turning it in 30 seconds early maybe for bragging purposes, idk</p><p>And they posted the solutions on the HMMT website immediately after the teamround ended, and we ended up not sillying anything and getting a perfect score, tnag orz</p><h2 id="Guts-Round"><a href="#Guts-Round" class="headerlink" title="Guts Round"></a>Guts Round</h2><p>alright this is when I really did absolutely nothing</p><p>We started pretty good in the first seven sets (perfect score on each), but we were a bit slow so we had to rush through the rest of the sets and unfortunately got 0 points in estimation. Still rank 10 which is like good compared to our scores in individual rounds lol.</p><h2 id="Other"><a href="#Other" class="headerlink" title="Other"></a>Other</h2><p>tnag went to int bee finals, tnag orz</p><p>I also went to both Friday night and the Sunday lectures because it’s my first time. On Friday I went to HackHMMT and unexpectedly met CorzdeTiger and Sunday stuff were interesting I guess? </p><h2 id="Estimates"><a href="#Estimates" class="headerlink" title="Estimates"></a>Estimates</h2><p>G 21.153, T 23.242, Total 44.395<br>G rk. 60, T rk. 60, Total rk. 70<br>I sold so bad :(<br>Let’s see how good an estimate of my score this is. I probably failed the M2 goal miserably</p><h2 id="Aftermath"><a href="#Aftermath" class="headerlink" title="Aftermath"></a>Aftermath</h2><p>I turned out to be not too bad at predicting?</p><p>Results:<br>G 20.153, T 24.242, Total 44.395<br>G rk. 89, T rk. 44, Total rk. 65</p><p>Kinda happy that I did have something in top 50 but also kinda sad for being that close to top 50 in general and overall (well it’s not actually that close, but I just felt I was so dumb for forgetting about the 195 case)</p><p>At least I’ve finally achieved one of my goals.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;yayy&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="math comp" scheme="http://example.com/categories/math-comp/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2024 AMC 10A</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/11/07/2024-AMC-10A/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/11/07/2024-AMC-10A/</id>
    <published>2024-11-08T01:29:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T19:43:25.760Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>oops, although I guess it’s not too bad <strong>(LONG RANT WARNING)</strong></p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Before"><a href="#Before" class="headerlink" title="Before"></a>Before</h2><p>I was like kinda nervous, because even though this wasn’t my first time taking the AMCs (actually 10th time), it’s the first time I’m taking it digitally, and I’m afraid that I would mess up. I probably had to be extra careful as I thought it’s easier to misclick something and ruin my entire test.</p><p>Last time I wasn’t rlly satisfied with my score (120 on an extremely easy test), so I don’t want to have bad time management again. I also hope that my AMC10 scores won’t be like my AMC8 ones (strictly decreasing arithmetic sequence). I sillied so bad in the past (4 sillies on AMC8 after reviewing my answers !!!)</p><h2 id="The-test"><a href="#The-test" class="headerlink" title="The test (?)"></a>The test (?)</h2><p>So although I was a bit nervous, I tried to tell myself to stay calm, that there’s always a 10B and I had little chances to get into JMO anyway. Still, I didn’t expect the Commons I (where we took the AMC10 in LHS) to be that crowded, which somehow made me even more anxious.</p><p>I originally wanted to use some kind of strategy like starting from the middle so that I would feel more confident, but then thought that would be worse as I might not even be able to solve those problems :(</p><p>I spent like 2 minutes solving p1 because I was so afraid I might silly the first problem. Then I looked at p2, and this was when all the disaster started.</p><p>I stared at the problem for 1 minute, trying to understand it, and finally understood it. But I was afraid that I would silly on the second problem, so I subtracted the two from each other and was stuck because I thought 300 / 0.3 = 100 <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>Then I was stuck for another 5 minutes</p><p>I decided that I shouldn’t be stuck on a problem for too long, so I moved on. But after doing every 5 problems, I was like “it’s impossible that p2 was so hard” and went back to get stuck for another 3 minutes. I felt so desperate when I couldn’t even do problem 2 when I was aiming for DHR, and couldn’t stay calm even though I tried to, until I found out that I solved 16 problems and there was 15 minutes left.</p><p>I briefly counted and found that I could only get a 109.5 (without any sillies), and I might really get a lower score than last year. Based on past experiences, I on average had 3 sillies per AMC, so I might not even make AIME <span class="github-emoji"><span>💀</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f480.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></p><p>I expected myself to panick even more after realizing this, but perhaps it’s that the problems later were easier, I did 18-22 pretty quickly, and also found my mistake in p2. In the last few minutes, I knew that I didn’t really have time to check my answers, so I only made sure that I didn’t click on the wrong option on the computer.</p><h2 id="After"><a href="#After" class="headerlink" title="After"></a>After</h2><p>I didn’t really check my answers with others since the digital version scrambled the questions and answer choices so that it’s harder to cheat (and I didn’t notice for a while). I knew I probably got a really bad score, considering that I could easily calculate wrong when I’m nervous. Anyways there’s still a B so hopefully I get a better score on that one :&lt;</p><p>===== Above was written before I knew the answers (and scores) =====</p><p>So turns out that I didn’t have any sillies, giving me a 136.5 (18 higher than expected). It’s still not a very good score considering people saying that this year’s test was also easy like last year, but enough to make me happy I guess. This is probably my first AMC without sillies, which is ironic as people on AoPS said that this was the most silliable test ever.</p><p>My distrib: 11111 11111 11111 11111 11bbb</p><p>By this time I’ve also finished taking 10B but I probably won’t write a blog about it because I’m lazy and I did very bad despite it’s much easier than 10A imo.</p><p>Hopefully 136.5 is enough to get DHR, MAA didn’t release the statistics this time so I dont really know, sad.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;oops, although I guess it’s not too bad &lt;strong&gt;(LONG RANT WARNING)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="math comp" scheme="http://example.com/categories/math-comp/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Goals for 24-25 School Year</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/10/28/Goals-for-24-25-School-Year/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/10/28/Goals-for-24-25-School-Year/</id>
    <published>2024-10-28T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-22T18:00:35.201Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems a bit too late, but whatever</p><span id="more"></span><p>Many people had been posting about their goals for the school year, so I guess I’ll make one too? So here are my goals, the goals in each category are rougly sorted by difficulty</p><p>Legend:</p><ul><li><span class="github-emoji"><span>✔</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2714.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> = <font color="green">successful</font></li><li><span class="github-emoji"><span>📈</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c8.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> = <font color="yellow">currently successful</font></li><li><span class="github-emoji"><span>❓</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2753.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> = nothing yet</li><li><span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> <font color="orange">currently failing</font></li><li><span class="github-emoji"><span>❌</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/274c.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span> = <font color="red">already failed</font></li></ul><h2 id="CP-C"><a href="#CP-C" class="headerlink" title="CP (C)"></a>CP (C)</h2><ul><li>First Place in LIT Standard Round MS Division <span class="github-emoji"><span>❓</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2753.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>CF maintain stable 2100+ by end of year <span class="github-emoji"><span>📈</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c8.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>AtCoder 1900+ <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>CF Peak IM <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li></ul><h2 id="USACO-U"><a href="#USACO-U" class="headerlink" title="USACO (U)"></a>USACO (U)</h2><ul><li>Plat <span class="github-emoji"><span>✔</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2714.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Plat by december <span class="github-emoji"><span>✔</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2714.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Get a positive score on each USACO plat contest <span class="github-emoji"><span>❌</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/274c.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Camp <span class="github-emoji"><span>❓</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2753.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li></ul><h2 id="Math-M"><a href="#Math-M" class="headerlink" title="Math (M)"></a>Math (M)</h2><ul><li>AMC 10 DHR <span class="github-emoji"><span>✔</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2714.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Get individual top 50 in something in HMMT November <span class="github-emoji"><span>✔</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2714.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Reach level 50 in OTIS <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>JMO qual <span class="github-emoji"><span>❓</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2753.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li></ul><h2 id="Other-O"><a href="#Other-O" class="headerlink" title="Other (O)"></a>Other (O)</h2><ul><li>Top 500 on CF contribution leaderboard <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>GPA 4.0+ <span class="github-emoji"><span>📈</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c8.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Stop being lazy <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li><li>Socialize <span class="github-emoji"><span>📉</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4c9.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span></li></ul><h2 id="Difficulty-order-in-my-opinion"><a href="#Difficulty-order-in-my-opinion" class="headerlink" title="Difficulty order (in my opinion)"></a>Difficulty order (in my opinion)</h2><p>C1 &lt; <font color="green">U1</font> &lt; <font color="green">M1</font> &lt; <font color="yellow">C2</font> &lt; <font color="orange">O1</font> &lt; <font color="green">U2</font> &lt; <font color="green">M2</font> &lt; <font color="yellow">O2</font> &lt; <font color="orange">M3</font> &lt; <font color="red">U3</font> &lt; <font color="orange">C3</font> &lt; <font color="orange">C4</font> &lt; M4 &lt; <font color="orange">O3</font> &lt; U4 &lt; <font color="orange">O4</font></p><p>I’m new here so idk what math contests they have and their difficulty rlly</p><p>Also I’m known for being bad at estimating difficulties of goals (I thought getting into USACO plat was way easier than reaching master on CF <span class="github-emoji"><span>😭</span><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f62d.png?v8" aria-hidden="true" onerror="this.parent.classList.add('github-emoji-fallback')"></span>)</p><p>Hopefully I can complete maybe 10 of the goals, tho everything above C4 seems impossible to me and I’m very good at sillying and being dumb</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seems a bit too late, but whatever&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Goals" scheme="http://example.com/categories/Goals/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World!</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/10/26/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/10/26/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2024-10-26T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-26T23:52:40.013Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>uhh</p><span id="more"></span><p>Hello 你好</p><h2 id="hi"><a href="#hi" class="headerlink" title="hi"></a>hi</h2><h3 id="hi-1"><a href="#hi-1" class="headerlink" title="hi"></a>hi</h3><figure class="highlight cpp"><table><tbody><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">cout &lt;&lt; <span class="string">"Hello World!\n"</span>;</span><br></pre></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;uhh&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Hello World" scheme="http://example.com/categories/Hello-World/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
